Federico Maguire Data Analyst | Data Science Enthusiast

Buenos Aires, Argentina

Portfolio: fedemaguire.github.io/MaguireDataAnalytics/

MaguireDataAnalytics@gmail.com linkedin.com/in/Federico-Maguire github.com/FedeMaguire

Data Analyst with a background in CAD/CAM, CNC, and 3D design. Developed skills in SQL, Excel, Python, Tableau, and Power BI through intensive training, specialized courses, certificates, and freelance work projects. Motivated to apply this expertise in a role that offers continuous opportunities for personal and professional growth.

SKILLS

- Python
- · SQL
- Excel
- Tableau
- Power Bi

- Web Scraping
- Data Visualization
- · Data Analysis
- Machine Learning
- Prompt Engineering

EXPERIENCE

Scale AI | May 2024 - Present Remote Python and SQL coder for AI training

Collaborated with cross-functional teams in various projects to optimize and integrate AI models through RLHF (Reinforcement Learning by Human Feedback).

- Evaluated and ensured safety, accuracy, efficiency, and adherence to best practices in LLM-generated responses to coding prompts across Python and SQL.
- Analyzing algorithms, optimizing queries and data structures, debugging techniques, ensuring code safety, and troubleshooting to provide optimal developer assistance.

Feelance Data Analyst | October 2023 - Present

Performed freelance data analysis work with Python, SQL, Excel, Tableau, and Power Bi.

- · Conducted data analysis to find useful insights and support decision-making.
- Developed visualizations to present findings effectively.
- Communicated results in a clear and understandable manner to clients/stakeholders.
- Contributed to multiple projects showcasing diverse data analysis skills.

PROJECT WORK

London Bike Sharing Data Analysis and Prediction

- Used Python for Exploratory Data Analysis (EDA) to uncover patterns in London bike sharing data, focusing on seasonal and weather-related trends.
- Created an interactive Tableau Dashboard to visualize weather's impact on bike rentals, facilitating intuitive insights.
- Developed a Linear Regression model to forecast rental demand based on seasonal variations and weather conditions.

2023 Data Job Postings Analysis World Map

- Cleaned and queried a dataset including 780,000 rows with salary information using PostgreSQL. Extracting valuable insights to address key questions about the data, uncovering trends and patterns related to salary information in the Data field.
- Findings were visualized in a **Tableau Dashboard**, in the form of a world map, gaining a visual understanding of the distribution of salaries. Valuable information to improve strategies for job seekers can be found in this project.

Other projects in Portfolio

- Coffe Sales analysis and interactive dashboard in Excel.
- Radio marketing campaign analysis and linear regression model with Python.
- Human Resourses SQL analysis and Power Bi dashboard.
- · Python Live data collection Trading Bot with user-friendly GUI.
- Python WhatsApp Chatbot with ChatGPT's API Integration and Database storage.

EDUCATION

Google Advanced Data Analytics Professional Certificate MAY 2023 - OCTOBER 2023

An extensive six month job-ready Google Career Certificate training. Hands-on experience with advanced Data Analytics practices and tools, including data science workflows, Python programming and Tableau. Exploratory data analysis, statistical data analysis, regression analysis, data modeling, and machine learning basics.

LANGUAGES

English Advance

Native

STRENGTHS

Teamwork

Experienced in collaborative environments and cross-functional teams to achieve project goals.

Active Listening

Great at really listening, connecting, and working together by understanding different viewpoints.

Fast Learnering

Rapidly acquiring new skills and technologies.

Attention to detail

Keen eye for detail aquired from 3D design projects and GCODE programming, effectively translated to data analysis and interpretation.

Adaptability

Quick to adapt to new environments and tasks.

Strong Analytical Skills

Trained in Data Analysis tools, with a solid foundation in statistical analysis, and data visualization.

Problem-Solving

Logical and analytical mindset, creative problemsolving solutions and accuracy in data-related contexts.

Effective Communication

Skilled in translating complex data into clear insights for decision-making purposes.

COURSES & CERTIFICATIONS

Google / Coursera (October 2023)

Career Essentials Data Analysis Microsoft / LinkedIn (April 2023)

The Complete Python Bootcamp Pierian Data / Udemy (March 2023)

The Complete SQL Bootcamp Pierian Data / Udemy (May 2023)

The Complete Excel Bootcamp
Pierian Data / Udemy (May 2023)

Python for Machine Learning & Data Science

Pierian Data / Udemy (June 2023)

Computational Thinking for Problem Solving

Penn University / Coursera (April 2023)

ChatGPT Prompt Engineering For Developers

DeepLearning.AI / OpenAI (May 2023)

INTERESTS

Continuous Learning

Continuous professional and personal development through active learning and skills improvement.

Data Science

Curious about the dynamic field of data science and machine learning, fascinated by the complexities of modeling and extracting predictions.

3D Design & 3D Printing

Enthusiastic about the creative possibilities of 3D design and the diverse applications of 3D printing technology.